我有一个很深的个人信念，
I have a deep personal conviction and
我想这是许多从事教学工作的人的共同信念，
I think it's shared by many in the courage to teach work
即人类历史上一些
that some of the greatest movements
最伟大的运动和时刻
and moments in human history
都来自于那些
have come from the lives of people who
内心深处决定
have made a very deep inner decision to
不再分裂的人的生活。
live divided no more.
我有时称其为罗莎 ・ 帕克斯决定，
I sometimes call it the Rosa Parks decision,
因为她在我们的社会中是
because she's so emblematic in our society
一个没有权力、地位、财富和
of someone who didn't have power and status and
影响力的人的象征，但她有一个自我。
wealth and clout, but who had a self.
1955年12月1日这天，
And one day December 1st 1955,
我记得在阿拉巴马州的蒙哥马利,
Montgomery Alabama as I recollect,
她决定不再
she decided that she would no longer
在外表上表现得
behave on the outside in a way that
与她内心深处对自己的了解
contradicted the truth she knew about
相矛盾的行为。
herselfhood on the inside.
她决定坐在公共汽车的前面,
She decided that she would sit at the front of the bus,
因为她是个身心完整的人,
because she was a full human being,
她内心知道这一点。
she knew that inwardly.
而现在她要把这一点向外表现出来。
And now she was going to act on that outwardly.
我们都知道这一行为
And we all know the huge consequences
所带来的巨大成果。
that flowed from that act.
我的意思不是说她是一个人做的，
I don't mean that she did it alone,
在那个地方和时间还有很多人。
there were many other people in that place and time.
然而就在那天，在那段旅程中，
And yet today who were on that journey
罗莎决定不再过分裂的生活。
towards living divided no more.
但我的意思是，如果没有像
But I do mean that without persons like
罗莎 ・ 帕克斯这样的人所做的
Rosa Parks making that decision and
并以公开的方式表现出来的决定，
manifesting it in a public way,
人类的历史永远不会变得更好。
human history will never change for the better.